alright let's get started welcome to the
好吧，让我们开始吧，欢迎来到
session on refactoring to functional
重构功能会议
style my name is Venkat Subramanyam
风格，我叫Venkat Subramanyam
we're going to talk about taking some
我们将要谈论一些
examples and infra-red a style and then
实例和红外线样式，然后
working our way through to functional
努力实现功能
style I'll talk a little bit about the
风格，我会谈一些
motivations for doing this some of the
这样做的动机
things we need to be concerned about and
我们需要关注的事情
then we'll jump into some examples and
然后我们进入一些例子
start looking at a few examples of how
开始看一些如何
we can do this and along the way we'll
我们可以做到这一点，并一路走来
talk about some approaches we could take
谈论我们可以采取的一些方法
so one of the things to consider is a
所以要考虑的一件事是
lot of mainstream languages in fact most
实际上大多数主流语言
of the mainstream languages that we've
我们已经拥有的主流语言
been using for the past 20 to 30 years
在过去20至30年中一直在使用
have been promoting imperative style of
一直在倡导命令式的
programming in imperative style of
命令式编程
programming we talked about how to do
编程我们谈到了怎么做
but we also proceeded to write code to
但我们也继续编写代码以
express how to do it so imperative style
表达如何做到这样势在必行
focuses on both what and how and it's
专注于什么以及如何以及它
the house that really gets into trouble
真正陷入困境的房子
because it gets us into trouble because
因为这给我们带来麻烦
it relates to accidental complexity what
它与意外复杂性有关
declarative programming we focus on
我们关注的声明式编程
saying what to do but not as much and on
说什么该做什么，但不那么反复
how to do it well functional style
如何做好函数式风格
inherently is declarative in style
本质上是声明式的
not all declarative code is functional
并非所有的声明性代码都起作用
but all functional code is actually
但是所有功能代码实际上都是
declarative that is one of the most
说明性的是最
charming features of programming and
编程和
functional style is that we can focus on
函数式风格是我们可以专注于
the wart and let underlying libraries
疣，让底层库
take care of how to actually do it but
照顾如何实际去做，但是
one of the challenges with java 8 is
Java 8的挑战之一是
unlike the previous versions of Java
不像以前的Java版本
Java 8 was not about syntactical change
Java 8与语法更改无关
it's actually a paradigm shift it
这实际上是一种范式转变
requires us to think very differently
要求我们以不同的方式思考
and program very differently and I'll be
和程序完全不同，我会
honest about this I spent several
老实说我花了几个
decades programming an imperative style
数十年编程势在必行
I can tell you that I spent my youth
我可以告诉你，我度过了我的青春
programming in a period of style that
在一段时期内编程
tells you that I had a terrible
告诉你我过得很糟糕
childhood and now I'm trying to recover
童年，现在我正试图恢复
from that and start programming in
从那开始编程
functional style and it's not natural
函数式风格，这是不自然的
for me I have to think really extra hard
对我来说，我必须加倍努力
to think in functional style and I have
以函数式风格思考，我有
to say that I'm probably about a 50%
说我大概是50％
level into it now if you throw a problem
如果您遇到问题，现在就进入它
at me maybe 50% of the time I can think
我大概有50％的时间在想我
functionally the other 50% I have to
从功能上来说，我还需要50％
struggle one of the most interesting
奋斗中最有趣的事情之一
experience was on a flight not too long
体验飞行时间不长
ago it was across Atlantic flight it
以前是穿越大西洋的
took about nine hours of flight I
我花了大约九个小时的时间
started with the problem in the
从问题开始
beginning of the flight and struggled
飞行开始并挣扎
with it for seven hours trying to write
用了七个小时试图写
in functional
在功能上
style I'll tell you it beats any
风格我会告诉你的
in-flight entertainment you can have and
您可以享受的机上娱乐
then when I was done with that it was
然后当我做完那件事时
like well why did I have so much
很好，为什么我有这么多
difficulty doing this because hindsight
这样做很困难，因为事后看来
is 20/20 once I had the solution at the
当我在解决方案上找到20/20
end of the seven hours it was like why
七个小时结束了，为什么
did I have so much trouble and what was
我有那么多麻烦吗？
really making it hard for me is my
我真的很难受
background my comfort level who really
我的舒适水平到底是谁
makes it hard for me to think
让我很难思考
differently so that's what I want to
不一样，所以这就是我想要的
focus on the paradigm shift how we can
专注于范式转变
approach this maybe in a way that can
可能以一种可以
make things a little bit easier for us
让事情变得更容易
as we consider shifting to functional
当我们考虑转向功能
style I'm not recommending taking
我不建议服用
existing code and changing them all to
现有代码并将其全部更改为
functional style I want to make that
我想要使​​函数式风格
very clear
非常清楚
I believe in producing value so there's
我相信创造价值，所以有
good code working just leave it at like
好的代码工作就像
the way it is for now but when you come
现在的样子，但是当你来的时候
down to fix the bug make an enhancement
修正错误以增强功能
or you're trying to revamp major parts
或者您正在尝试改造主要部件
of it that's a really good time for us
对我们来说这是一个非常美好的时光
to revisit and maybe change the code but
重新访问并可能更改代码，但是
also as we sit down to write code we can
当我们坐下来编写代码时，我们也可以
clearly write it very quickly
清楚地写得很快
imperatively the new code but then maybe
命令性的新代码，但也许
transform it functional style that's a
转换它的函数式风格
really good way to learn as well as we
和我们一样，是一个非常好的学习方式
get very comfortable with the style of
变得非常自在
programming so let's get into some
编程，让我们进入一些
exercises and play with some examples
练习和玩一些例子
here I want to start from the very first
我想从头开始
example I'm going to focus on five
例子我将专注于五个
different examples in this presentation
本演示文稿中的不同示例
given the time so let's see what we can
给定时间，让我们看看我们能做什么
do first I'm gonna start with an
首先我要从
imperative style of programming code to
势在必行的编程代码
begin with well I mentioned that
首先我提到
imperative style is where we say what to
命令式的风格是我们说什么
do but also we say how to do it let's
做，但我们也说如何做，让我们
take a look at an example real quick
快速看一个例子
here
这里
I have a little function here on the
我在这里有一个小功能
main that's looping through and telling
遍历并讲述的主要
whether the numbers 1 through 7 are
数字1到7是否为
prime numbers or not well they say never
素数还是不好，他们说永不
refactor code that doesn't work well
重构效果不佳的代码
this sum seems to be working ideally I
这笔款项似乎运作理想
would have automated tests for it but in
会有自动化测试，但是
this case this is good enough for what
这种情况足以满足
we do here so in this case of course
我们当然是在这种情况下
it's working and giving us the result
它正在工作并给我们结果
but here is the East prime method of not
但这是东方的主要方法
try to be very smart about this method
尝试对这种方法非常聪明
I'm not trying to make it very efficient
我不是想使其变得非常有效
just take a very simple looping I say 4
我只是说一个非常简单的循环4
and then of course I loop through this
然后我当然循环
for loop ask if a number is divisible by
for循环询问数字是否可被整数整除
that range of numbers if so I set the
该数字范围，如果可以的话
variable to possible and then I exit out
可能的变量，然后我退出
of it now if you look at this this is a
现在，如果你看这个，这是一个
very reminiscent of a lot of stuff we do
非常让人想起我们做的很多事情
folks there are some chairs in the
乡里有一些椅子
right if you want to just walk through
对，如果你只是想穿过
the front please feel free to do that so
前台请随时这样做
there's a lot of seats in the front over
前面有很多座位
here and and if there's a seat next to
在这里，如果旁边有座位
you just raise your hand so it's easier
你只要举起手就更容易了
for people to okay - well thank you very
人们可以-很好，非常感谢
much appreciate it okay so let's look at
非常感谢，好吧，让我们来看一下
this code for a second and see what it
这段代码一秒钟，看看它是什么
really says well I have a challenge for
说真的，我有一个挑战
you when you go back to work on Monday
你星期一回去上班时
do this for me do what we grab on for in
为我做这个，为我们做些什么
your source code and be scary how many
您的源代码，并害怕多少
four loops we use this is like somebody
我们使用的四个循环就像有人
knocks on their door II opened the door
敲门II打开门
there's a guy with the hammer you ask
你问有一个人用锤子
him what he's there for he says I'm here
他在那儿，因为他说我在这里
to fix your kitchen you say re don't you
修理你的厨房，你说不是吗
are you not gonna use any tools he says
你会不会使用任何他说的工具
I got a hammer I don't need any other
我有锤子，我不需要任何其他东西
stinking tools you probably will let
可能会让您发臭的工具
this guy in and go out and call the cops
这个家伙进去出去叫警察
it's not safe to be in the house anymore
呆在家里不安全了
right well that's what we've been doing
好吧，这就是我们一直在做的
been using this for hammer for
一直用这个锤子
everything we do and and it's insane
我们所做的一切，而且很疯狂
that everything is for and occasionally
一切都是为了偶尔
a while loop that we use but in this
我们使用的while循环
case what did we do we loop through and
案例我们做了什么，我们遍历了
then check for a condition and then set
然后检查条件，然后设置
the boolean to be visible to be true and
布尔值是可见的，并且为真
then we have to control the looping but
然后我们必须控制循环
let's put this in English what are we
让我们用英语写这是什么
really doing well why should we put in
真的很好，为什么我们要投入
in English the reason I put it in
用英语我把它放进去的原因
English is it really makes us to think
英语真的让我们思考
about what we are doing and that can
关于我们在做什么，那可以
help us to capture the essence of the
帮助我们把握精髓
wort and then we can look for methods
麦汁，然后我们可以寻找方法
that actually translates English to code
实际上将英语翻译成代码
so let's see what we are doing given a
所以让我们看一下我们在做什么
number we want to find the range of
我们要查找的范围数
numbers so that no value in the range
数字，因此范围内没有值
divides the given number so that's a
除以给定的数字，所以这是一个
little formulation that can actually
实际上很少的配方
help us to think about it a little bit
帮助我们考虑一下
better so let's give it a try and see
更好，让我们尝试一下
how we can rewrite this code in more of
我们如何在更多内容中重写此代码
a functional style so I'm gonna start
一种实用的风格，所以我要开始
importing in this case Java dot util
在这种情况下导入Java dot util
let's say darts dreamed out star and I
假设飞镖梦见了星星，而我
said range of numbers well the word
说数字范围很好这个词
range immediately prompts us to think
范围立即促使我们思考
about an int stream so I'm gonna go
关于一个int流，所以我要去
ahead and call this as in stream so
向前并称其为流中
we'll say return number is greater than
我们会说返回数大于
one and and into stream dot range from
一和成流点范围从
two to the given number well notice the
给定数字两个，请注意
for loop went from two to one list and
for循环从两个列表变为一个列表，
the number that's exactly what range
确切的数字范围
does as well it goes from the number two
它也从第二开始
of the number minus one the range closed
的数量减去闭合范围的一
will include
会包括
number but range doesn't so we have the
数字，但范围不大，所以我们有
range of numbers let's again go back to
数字范围让我们再次回到
English I say that given a number the
我说英语给定一个数字
known number in the given range divides
给定范围内的已知数除
the given number well in other words
换句话说，给定的数字很好
nothing matches our divisibility
没有什么比我们的除数更合适
criteria and the method we are looking
我们正在寻找的标准和方法
for here is called none match and then
因为这里叫做不匹配，然后
given a number in the range number Mart
给定范围Mart中的数字
I that we are interested is equal to
我感兴趣的等于
zero so that code in the table that you
零，以便表中的代码
saw here translates to a very small
看到这里转化为很小
piece of code in the bottom I mentioned
我在底部提到的一段代码
that we have been using the for hammer a
我们一直在用锤子
lot in the past but this one is using
过去很多，但是这个正在使用
very specialized methods little little
非常专业的方法
methods little tools it's like you hit a
方法小工具，就像您打了一个
knock on the door again you open the
再次敲门，您打开
door there's a guy with a little bag and
门上有一个有小书包的家伙，
you ask him what he's there for to fix
你问他他在那里要修理什么
the kitchen he lays up the tools and you
厨房，他放好工具，你
say wow look at that there's a real
说哇，看看有一个真正的
wrench there's a little screwdriver
扳手有一把小螺丝刀
there's a little chisel well those are
有一些凿子
the tools of his trade right you ask him
你问他交易权的工具
are you gonna use all of those tools he
你会用所有这些工具吗
says the one who uses all the tools is
说使用所有工具的人是
called a consultant no I'm gonna use
叫顾问不，我要用
only what makes sense for the project
只有对项目有意义的
and the point really is we're gonna use
关键是我们要使用
these little specialized tools to get
这些小小的专业工具
our work done and that's exactly what
我们的工作完成了，这就是
the range function and the non match
范围函数和不匹配
function are going to do for us as you
功能将像您一样为我们做
can see that result of that code is
可以看到该代码的结果是
exactly the same as before but what we
和以前完全一样，但是我们
did was we translated that fluffy code
是我们翻译了蓬松的代码吗
in front of us into something very
在我们面前变得非常
highly expressive I'm not looking for
表现力很强我不是在寻找
code that is short that is not the
短的代码不是
objective what I want is code that is
客观的我想要的是
concise but also very expressive that is
简洁但又很有表现力的是
what I'm really after you take much less
你少花钱之后我到底在想什么
effort to read this code and understand
努力阅读此代码并理解
once we know what range and non-match
一旦我们知道范围和不匹配
means of course that becomes a lot
当然意味着很多
easier to work with so that is an
更容易使用，所以这是一个
example of how we can use some of these
我们如何使用其中一些示例
ideas to create a little function that
创建一个小功能的想法
can tell us whether a number is prime
可以告诉我们数字是否为质数
but more so to really iterate over the
但更重要的是要真正遍历
range of values and get the result we
取值范围并得到结果
are looking for so that's less noise no
正在寻找，以减少噪音
garbetts variables that divisible was a
garbetts变量是可除的
garbage variable we're not introducing
我们不介绍的垃圾变量
unnecessary variables here and of course
这里，当然还有不必要的变量
we used higher-order functions we are
我们使用了高阶函数
passing the function to the function
将函数传递给函数
which is an unmatched function so that
这是无与伦比的功能
really helped us quite a bit here let's
真的帮助了我们很多，让我们
go on to the next
继续下一个
example here again from imperative but
例子再次从命令，但
in this case we're going to go to a
在这种情况下，我们要去
functional style of code and I want to
功能代码的风格，我想
know how many lines in my text contains
知道我的文字中包含多少行
a certain word now in order to do this
现在一定要这样做
how would we write the code for it in
我们将如何在其中编写代码
the traditional Java let's take a look
传统的Java让我们看一下
at an example here so I have a little
在这里的一个例子，所以我有一点
main function as you can see here and
您可以在这里看到的主要功能和
this main function starts up and first
该主要功能启动并首先
of all opens up a bufferedreader and
所有这些都会打开一个bufferedreader，
connects to a file reader as you can see
如您所见，连接到文件阅读器
and it's opening up my ADC host file I'm
它正在打开我的ADC主机文件
interested in searching for the word
有兴趣寻找这个词
localhost and I want to know how many
localhost ，我想知道多少
lines contain the word localhost so what
行包含单词localhost，那么
am I doing here I first of all create a
我在这里做什么我首先创建一个
line and set it to null and we all know
行并将其设置为null，我们都知道
that null is a smell and then we go
那空是一种气味，然后我们去
ahead and say while line is equal to
前面说，而线等于
bufferedreader dot read line is not
bufferedreader点读取行不是
equal to null
等于null
it's code like this we should never show
像这样的代码我们不应该显示
the children because the minute they
孩子们，因为他们一刻
look at it they say heck I've never will
看着他们，他们说我永远不会
be in this profession again and they do
再次进入这个行业，他们会
something else would rather be
宁愿有其他事情
accountants than doing this right so the
会计师比做这项权利，所以
point really is and not that it's bad to
重点确实是
be accountants by any means though but I
无论如何都要当会计师，但是我
would rather be writing clear and
宁愿写得清楚，
concise code so the point really in this
简洁的代码，所以重点在此
case is I really don't want to be really
情况是我真的不想真的
writing code this is clumsy and so
编写代码很笨拙，所以
imperative and noisy then what do we do
当务之急和嘈杂，然后我们该怎么办
we check if lines contains that
我们检查行是否包含
particular word and then we increment
特定的词，然后我们递增
the count again and then we keep looping
再次计数，然后我们继续循环
through it that's a lot of ceremony in
通过它，很多仪式在
our code and when we are done finally we
我们的代码，最后完成后，我们
declare the win and report the word
宣布获胜并举报
contain the occurs that many times in
包含多次发生
the file well so how do we really work
文件很好，那么我们如何真正工作
through this very differently this is
通过这个非常不同的是
one of the things that really excites me
真正让我兴奋的一件事
about Java eight is they just didn't
关于Java八，他们只是没有
deliver lambdas and walk away they then
交付lambda，然后走开
took a very decisive approach to
采取了非常果断的方法
enhancing the JDK to improve all the
增强JDK以改善所有
different methods that can be really
可能确实是不同的方法
functional in nature so let's see what
本质上是功能性的，让我们看看
I'm gonna do here now I'm gonna take
我现在要在这里做
this code right here and let's go ahead
这段代码就在这里，让我们继续
and comment this code out for just a
然后将此代码注释掉
minute so we can actually refactor it
分钟，以便我们实际进行重构
and I've called this variable as count
我称这个变量为count
so I'm gonna say a long that count is
所以我要说的是
equal to but how am I gonna find the
等于但我将如何找到
count of this well the very for
算是很好
thing I'm gonna do here is I'm gonna go
我要在这里做的是我要去
ahead and import a Java dot n io dart
并导入一个Java dot n io dart
file and then in this case I'm gonna use
文件，然后在这种情况下，我将使用
the class which is the files class in
属于文件类的类
fact let's take a little bit of baby
事实上，让我们带一点儿孩子
steps to come to it so pardon me let's
采取步骤，请原谅我
go ahead and run this first before we
继续并先运行这个
try to modify this I'll come back to
尝试修改它，我会回到
this in just a second and then of course
只需一秒钟，然后当然
when I go back and run this we do want
当我回去运行它时，我们确实想要
to make sure the result is actually the
确保结果实际上是
same it said occurred three times I want
它说我想发生过三次
the same result when I'm done with this
完成此操作后得到相同的结果
great now let's go back here and just
太好了，让我们回到这里
comment out this piece of code for a
注释掉这段代码
second and let's take a bit of a baby
第二，让我们带一个孩子
step in getting towards this let's go
迈向这一步，让我们开始吧
ahead and bring in Java dot IO dot file
提前并引入Java点IO点文件
dot star and in this case let's go ahead
点星，在这种情况下，让我们继续
and say over here files and then dart
然后在这里说文件然后飞镖
lines and then this is going to be the
行，然后这将是
lines method and this takes a path yet
线法，这需要一条路径
and I'm interested in the path to what
我对通往什么的道路感兴趣
is the file I'm interested in well
是我感兴趣的文件
that's the path I'm interested in so
这就是我感兴趣的道路
I'll use the path variable right here
我将在此处使用path变量
and so I'm gonna ask you to give me the
所以我要请你给我
path of that particular code that's what
该特定代码的路径就是
I'm asking for so a pad start get so
我要的是这样的开始
what does that really give us let's
真正给我们带来了什么？
quickly take a look at what this
快看看这是什么
function returns to us and thankfully
函数返回给我们，谢天谢地
what this is doing is it's returning to
这是在做什么
us a stream which is really nice so now
我们流真的很好，所以现在
that we have a stream on our hand we can
我们手边有一条小溪，我们可以
use the stream API to do further
使用流API进行进一步操作
processing so what I'm gonna do now is
处理，所以我现在要做的是
now that I have all the lines in the
现在我已经将所有行
file I'll say filter over here and then
我会在这里说过滤器
I will say given a line that is given to
我会说给定一条线
me
我
let's say line dot contains exactly the
假设线点正好包含
code that we did right here but we cut
我们在这里所做的代码，但我们削减了
through all that other fluff by now and
通过所有其他的绒毛现在
then we asked for the search word we are
然后我们要求搜索词
interested in and that really gives us
感兴趣，这真的给了我们
the number all the lines that meet the
符合的所有行数
criteria and then we set that to a count
标准，然后我们将其设置为一个计数
and then now of course we can simply say
然后我们当然可以简单地说
long account is equal to and then we can
多头账户等于，然后我们可以
set that into that variable right off
马上将其设置到该变量中
the bat right there and then so when we
蝙蝠在那里，然后当我们
run this code now we can see that it
现在运行此代码，我们可以看到它
gives us the same result as before but
给我们和以前一样的结果，但是
we didn't have to put in so much effort
我们不必付出太多的努力
to do this so the Lions method of files
为此，狮子的文件方法
gives us really nicely the ability to
确实给了我们很好的能力
get a stream out of this and process it
得到一个流并对其进行处理
so we can again
这样我们可以再次
of all that ceremony in the code and we
代码中所有的仪式，我们
can use a functional style of coding for
可以使用功能性的编码方式
this so lines gives us a stream and
这样行就给我们一个流，
given the stream we get all the lines
给定流，我们得到所有的线条
that meet this criteria whatever that
符合这个标准的
criteria is and in the end we do a count
标准是，最后我们做了一个计数
of it and get the result out of it and
并从中获得结果
that's exactly what we did in this
这正是我们所做的
example so that's another way to look at
例子，这是另一种看待方式
it so we saw the nun match in the in
所以我们在里面看到了修女比赛
stream now we are looking at files in
流，我们正在看文件
the in lines in the files
文件中的行
class itself and these are all helping
上课本身，这些都在帮助
us to get our work done a little bit
我们把工作做好一点
more effectively
更有效地
once again no explicit variables we're
再次没有明确的变量
using the stream and the filter method
使用流和过滤方法
to accomplish our job in this case let's
在这种情况下完成我们的工作，让我们
go a little further now things can get
现在可以走得更远
really ugly when we try to do a little
当我们尝试做一点时真的很丑
bit more complex things we're gonna look
我们要看的更复杂的东西
at a firmly verbose code to do something
用固定的冗长代码来做某事
really simple this is when you realize
真的很简单，这是当你意识到
the problem is simple but the solution
问题很简单，但是解决方法
becomes overly complex and that's when
变得过于复杂，那时候
you know we are heading in the wrong
你知道我们走错了方向
direction you don't want the solution to
您不想要解决方案的方向
be more complex than the problem really
比问题真正复杂
we have that would be the accidental
我们认为那是偶然的
complexity let's look at one example of
复杂性让我们看一个例子
this to see what this really means so I
看看这到底意味着什么，所以我
have a little main here with these
这些有一些主要的
scores as you can see right here what
您在这里看到的分数
this course is doing is it's putting a
本课程正在做的是
bunch of names and score values into
一堆名字和分数值变成
this map so in card people's name
这张地图以卡人的名字命名
potentially and score values but what I
可能和分数值，但我
want to really do is print out who has
真正想做的是打印出谁拥有
all who all have a common score so let's
所有的人都有共同的分数，所以让我们
go ahead and run this code to take a
继续并运行此代码以采取
look at it Tom and Nancy have a score of
看它，汤姆和南希的得分为
11 Jack is the sole person with 12
11杰克是12岁的唯一人
Darla's Nick and Jill have a score of 15
达拉（Darla）的尼克（Nick）和吉尔（Jill）得分为15
but the question is how do we really do
但问题是我们如何真正做到
this in the imperative style you can
以命令式的风格可以
just imagine how much effort we're going
想像一下我们要付出多少努力
to put to do this you first create a map
为此，您首先创建一张地图
of course with the score values and a
当然还有分数值和
list of names that's where the trouble
麻烦的名字列表
that starts is ended then you get one
开始就结束了，那么你得到一个
score value does this exist in the map
分数值是否存在于地图中
already no it doesn't create an empty
已经没有它不会创建一个空的
list insert the empty list insert the
列表插入空列表插入
name into that anybody wants to do that
有人想这样做的名字
absolutely ridiculous isn't it but
绝对是荒谬的，但是
that's the kind of code we've been
这就是我们一直以来的代码
writing for years where this simply
多年写作
sucks the life out of us as we start
一开始就让我们感到烦恼
writing this code in
编写此代码
very smart developers never write this
非常聪明的开发人员永远不会写这个
code we hire interns to do this stuff
我们雇用实习生来做这些事情的代码
and and that's why this becomes really
这就是为什么这变得真正
tedious to work on and it's not fun at
工作很乏味，而且在
all
所有
doing something like this over time so
随着时间的推移做这样的事情
what can we do to improve this it is
我们可以做些什么来改善它
insane because remember what functional
疯狂，因为记住什么功能
style does you tell what to do and you
风格会告诉你做什么，你
let underlying libraries figure out how
让底层库找出如何
to do it so you can look at all these
做到这一点，所以你可以看看所有这些
lines in front of us about ten lines of
我们面前的十行
code is gonna just disappear in front of
代码只会消失在
our eyes
我们的眼睛
within seconds right now so let's go
现在几秒钟​​之内，让我们开始吧
back over here to this little code right
回到这里这个小代码吧
here and then grab the entire function
在这里，然后抓住整个功能
comment that out and then what we're
评论出来，然后我们是什么
gonna do is return well we're gonna
要做的就是回报我们要
start with the scores that's coming in
从即将出现的分数开始
as an input right here so we're gonna
作为输入，所以我们要
start with this scores right here but
从这里的分数开始，但是
we're gonna say in this case key set and
在这种情况下，我们要说的是
I'm gonna simply get the key set from
我要简单地从
this particular scores and then again
这个特定的分数，然后再次
ask for a stream out of it then we're
要求流出来，然后我们
gonna ask a collect now before I go
我要去之前先问个收藏
further into the collect I want to spend
进一步进入我想花的钱
a little a few seconds talking about one
几秒钟谈论一个
thing that is very very important which
非常重要的事情
is called a collectors if you have not
如果您还没有的话，被称为收藏家
had a chance to I highly recommend you
有机会我强烈推荐你
spend a Friday evening with collectors
与收藏家度过一个星期五晚上
your night would be wonderful I promise
我保证你的夜晚会很棒
you because collectors is such a wealth
你，因为收藏家是如此的富有
in the JDK I keep discovering the power
在JDK中，我不断发现力量
of collectors time and again and there
的收藏家一次又一次
are so many wonderful methods within
有很多很棒的方法
collectors and and it's it's one of
收藏家，这是其中之一
those API is that's as powerful as
这些API的功能与
anything else could be and so it gives
任何其他可能是，所以它给
you a lot of these api's are convenience
您很多这些api都很方便
methods to do certain operations on
在某处执行某些操作的方法
collecting things so collectors is one
收集东西，所以收藏家是其中之一
of my most favorite classes utility
我最喜欢的类实用程序
classes in the JDK so I'm gonna come
JDK中的课程，所以我要来
down to the collector method and I'm
到收集器方法，我
gonna say grouping by in this case given
在这种情况下会说分组
a particular person's name I want to
我想要的特定人的名字
group the values based on scores don't
根据分数将值分组
get the name or to get the scores of the
得到名字或得到分数
name itself and you can see how the
自己命名，您可以看到
research is exactly like what you just
研究就像你一样
saw earlier but of course some of you
见过较早，但当然有人
are not too happy because I wrote too
不太开心，因为我也写了
much code here will reduce it even
这里很多代码甚至会减少它
further now so I can now say take this
现在更远，所以我现在可以说接受这个
one and say well okay we can act
一个说好吧，我们可以采取行动
we make use of method references in Java
我们利用Java中的方法引用
8 so we can take this one and say scores
8所以我们可以拿这个说分数
double : get and we can write it much
double：获取，我们可以写很多东西
more concisely as well so why write more
还要更简洁，为什么还要写更多
code than necessary and you can see this
代码超过必要，您可以看到
so if you ever want to get into a
因此，如果您想进入
competition ask one of your colleagues
竞争问你的一位同事
to write that code and while they're
编写代码，而他们
still starting up you can write this
还在启动，你可以写这个
code and eat their lunch so that is one
编码并吃午餐，这是一个
of the beautiful things about how
关于如何美丽的事情
concise this is and it's pretty insane
简而言之，这很疯狂
how powerful this is you're saying given
你说这有多强大
all the scores get me their key set and
所有的分数都给我他们的关键
then go through a iteration on the
然后在
streams using the streams on the key set
使用密钥集上的流
and then just start grouping them based
然后开始根据它们进行分组
on the score values for those names and
这些名称的得分值和
that's we turned those set you know 10
那就是我们把那些你知道的10
lines of code into some will argue 3
几行代码会争论3
lines of code but I always argue because
代码行，但我总是争辩因为
there was only one semicolon that's just
只有一个分号
one line of code so so that's basically
一行代码，所以基本上
how concise it is that you can actually
您实际上可以多么简洁
make it very powerful as we can see
如我们所见，它变得非常强大
that's yet again a wonderful things we
那又是一件很棒的事情
can do with the library of functions
可以使用功能库
available to us which is pretty pretty
提供给我们，这很漂亮
darn nice so the code is very highly
很好，所以代码非常高
expressive it's very declarative in
富有表现力的
nature but of course in this case we use
自然，但在这种情况下，我们当然使用
some very specialized functions and that
一些非常专业的功能
is something that's going to take a
这将需要一个
little bit of time and getting used to
一点时间和习惯
because when it comes to some of these
因为当涉及到其中一些
functions we do have to take the time to
我们必须花一些时间来完成的功能
figure out what functions are available
找出可用的功能
so there are two approaches I think we
所以我认为有两种方法
should kind of take to understand this
应该有点理解
one is when you formulate the problem in
一种是您在制定问题时
English you can go back and ask the
英语，你可以回去问
question is there functions I know of
问题是我知道的功能吗
that kind of matches these kinds of
这种匹配这些类型的
actions and you can do this the other
行动，你可以做到这一点
thing I normally do is you know
我通常要做的是你知道
everybody has only limited relative
每个人只有有限的亲戚
ability to remember things we can't
记住我们无法记住的事情的能力
remember everything unfortunately but as
不幸的是，记住一切
I kind of walk through the JDK as a walk
我有点像漫步JDK
through libraries as it just brought
通过图书馆带来的
browse to the documentation I would come
浏览到我会来的文档
across methods I probably have never
我可能从来没有跨过方法
seen and immediately I would take a note
看到，我马上记下
of it I would just pass for a minute and
我会通过一分钟
take a look at it and say hey what in
看一看，说嘿
the world it is doing and it's just in
它正在做的世界，就在
the back of my mind and another day when
我的后脑和另一天
I'm working on something else I might
我正在做其他事情
say oh yeah I remember seeing that
说哦，是的，我记得看到过
little method back then and then I would
那时的小方法然后我会
go look at it at that time or I would
去看那个时候，否则我会
put it away for maybe experimentation
收起来进行实验
over maybe a free time that week
过了一周的空闲时间
and I will play with some of those
我会和其中一些一起玩
methods to see what they do and that
看他们做什么的方法
just becomes part of your you know a
成为你的一部分，你知道
capillary as you program and just like
毛细管在您编程时就像
the groups by method one of my other
我的方法之一
favorite methods is a method that can
最喜欢的方法是可以
help us to split a collection into a
帮助我们将集合拆分为
couple of different things for example
例如几个不同的东西
well you know I was giving a talk
你知道我在讲
recently and when somebody said hey I
最近有人说嘿我
understand filter very clearly if I have
如果我有很清楚地了解过滤器
a collection I can filter out maybe only
我可以过滤掉的收藏集
objects of a certain value let's say for
一定值的对象
a minute just as a crude example if I
一分钟，作为一个粗略的例子，如果我
want to separate this room into two
想要把这个房间分成两部分
parts I want people who are older than
我想要的部分比
me and people who are younger than me
我和比我年轻的人
well that would be a filter if I say
好吧，如果我说那将是一个过滤器
only people have anger than me would be
只有别人比我生气
a filter and what that collection would
过滤器以及该收集的内容
have is people younger than me but what
有比我年轻的人，但是
if I really want to collections those
如果我真的想收藏那些
are anger than me and those older than
比我和那些年纪大的人生气
me well further would not help you with
我进一步不会帮助你
that but the beauty of that is you can
那是美丽的是你可以
actually use in that case a partition by
在这种情况下实际使用分区
method and a partition by will give you
方法和分区将给您
this collection a map which is going to
此收藏将要去的地图
have one part which is in this example
在这个例子中只有一部分
people younger than me and the other
比我和其他人年轻的人
part of what older than me for example
比我年龄大的一部分
so you can use some things like that
所以你可以使用一些类似的东西
very nicely to achieve this let's look
非常好的实现这一点，让我们来看
at one other thing this example actually
另一方面，这个例子实际上
I would be I have to say was actually
我不得不说实际上
inspired by somebody who attended my
受到参加我的人的启发
previous talk they they attended the
他们参加的先前的演讲
talk and they emailed me and said I came
谈话，他们给我发电子邮件说我来了
to your talk really you know excited to
真的很高兴
see this but my problem is here is what
看到这个，但我的问题是什么
I'm trying to do and I can't figure out
我正在尝试做，但我不知道
from the examples you gave me how in the
从您给我的例子中
world to achieve this so I really thank
世界实现这一目标，所以我非常感谢
the person for the question gave an
有问题的人给了
answer and I kind of said that's a great
回答，我有点说那很棒
example so I'm going to replace one of
例子，所以我要替换其中之一
my examples to use this particular
我的例子来使用这个特殊的
example so let's take a look at what
例子，让我们看一下
this person wanted me to work with so
这个人要我一起工作
here is a little example of Euclid's
这是欧几里得的一个小例子
algorithm and all this is doing is given
算法，这一切都在给出
a collector numbers it wants to give you
一个想要给你的收藏家编号
a collection of numbers where the
一组数字
property that a square and a plus B
一个正方形加B的属性
square is equal to C square so for
平方等于C平方，因此
example give me all the numbers for
举例给我所有的数字
which this property of a square plus B
该属性的平方加B
Square equal to C square is met and if
满足等于C平方的平方，如果
for example when I run this code you
例如当我运行此代码时
will see three four and five meter
会看到三四五米
criteria three square plus four square
标准三平方加四平方
is equal to 25 which is five square so a
等于25等于5平方所以
b and c are three four and five and so
b和c是三个四和五个，依此类推
on but that's an infinite number of
上，但这是无限的
numbers you could actually look for but
您实际上可以寻找的数字，但是
the person wanted me to show how to
该人要我展示如何
solve this problem
解决这个问题
the gentleman actually sent me the code
这位先生实际上给我发了密码
when the imperative style and said hey i
当命令式和说嘿我
could do it this way I've got a function
可以这样做，我有一个功能
called get triple you can make things a
叫得到三倍，你可以使事情
little easier which is returning a
有点容易，这是返回一个
string here so get triple is simply
字符串在这里，所以获得三倍只是
returning the a B and C values for which
返回为其的B和C值
this criteria is being met and that's
符合这个标准，那就是
this you could algorithm to do this but
这你可以算法做到这一点，但
I want all the numbers up to a certain
我希望所有数字都达到一定
number let's say so in this case you
这么说吧，在这种情况下，您
notice what I have is a very traditional
注意我拥有的是非常传统的
code we start with a for loop on M going
我们从M上的for循环开始的代码
from 2 to M plus 1 and then of course
从2到M加1然后是
I'm sorry m equal to 2 2 all the way up
对不起，m等于2 2
incrementing by M plus incrementing m
递增M加递增m
and n of course starts with 1 but falls
n当然从1开始但下降
one-shot of M in that sequence and then
按此顺序一次拍摄M，然后
we go a call to get triple for M and n
我们打电话给M和n取三倍
and then we add it to the triple we
然后将其添加到三元组中
increase the count and if the count is
增加计数，如果计数是
greater than the number of values we
大于我们的价值
expected
预期
then we break out of the loop and then
然后我们跳出循环，然后
of course this is really sad isn't it
当然，这真的很可悲，不是吗
you have to do this check one more time
你必须再做一次检查
this is how imperative code punishes you
这就是命令性代码如何惩罚您
twice and so you have to really check
两次，所以你必须真正检查
again as well and then you break our
再一次，然后你打破我们
definitive there triples so the question
确定的在那里三倍，所以问题
is how do you really do this notice that
您实际上是如何做到这一点的
we have two for loops in this code and
在这段代码中我们有两个for循环
that's a bit confusing how do I deal
这有点令人困惑
with two for loops I know how to deal
有两个for循环，我知道如何处理
with one for loop I can use a range
与一个for循环，我可以使用一个范围
method I can use a filter I can use a
我可以使用过滤器的方法
stream I could use a map but here I have
流，我可以使用地图，但在这里
two for loops how in the world do I deal
两个for循环我该如何处理
with it well to understand this I'm
很好理解我
gonna take a slightly different example
将以一个稍微不同的例子
to illustrate how we would work with
说明我们将如何合作
this so imagine just for a minute
所以想像一下
I have a collection of person take
我有一个人带的集合
example of people in this room we got
这个房间里的人的例子
wonderful people in this room so I have
这个房间里的人很棒，所以我有
people in the room so I have a
房间里的人，所以我有一个
collection of people with me and what I
和我在一起的人和我的收藏
want is every person has a function
想要每个人都有功能
called get a primary email so everyone
打电话给主邮件，这样每个人
this room has a email a primary email
这个房间有一封电子邮件和一封主要电子邮件
I'm I'm sorry I don't want you but I
对不起，我不要你，但我
want your email address so I can spam
想要您的电子邮件地址，以便我可以发送垃圾邮件
you what a great idea so how do we do
您好主意，我们该怎么做
this well the function here is a
很好，这里的功能是
one-to-one mapping
一对一映射
meaning given a person you get an email
意味着给某人一个电子邮件
of the person so what are you use for
该人的，所以你用什么
that you say people dot map and then you
你说人点图，然后你
say person and you can say person dot
说人，你可以说人点
get primary email and that's basically
得到主要的电子邮件，基本上
how you would do this in your code so
您将如何在代码中执行此操作
you can get the primary email very
你可以得到主要的电子邮件
nicely so that works really well as you
很好，所以和你一样很好
can see how well we're on the other hand
可以看到我们的状况如何
if I have another function which is get
如果我还有另一个功能
all email addresses let's just say all
所有的电子邮件地址，让我们只说全部
emails this is going to return a
电子邮件这将返回一个
collection of all your email addresses
您所有电子邮件地址的集合
some of you may have one email I - some
你们中有些人可能只有一封电子邮件我-有些人
of you may have - some of you may have
你们当中可能有人-你们当中有人
seven I mean it's so much fun to spam
七，我的意思是，垃圾邮件非常有趣
all the addresses not just one of them
所有的地址不只是其中之一
isn't it so I want to map people to all
是不是所以我想将人们映射到所有人
their email addresses sadly this is a
他们的电子邮件地址很遗憾，这是一个
one-to-many because I go from a person
一对多，因为我来自一个人
to get email all emails and so this is
获取所有电子邮件的电子邮件，所以这是
emails not email anymore if I said
如果我说，电子邮件不再发送电子邮件了
peopled a person or people rather dot
一个人或一个人宁愿点
map given a person person d'art get all
给某人的地图d'art获得所有
emails well what do you get as a result
很好地向您发送电子邮件，结果
you go from a collection of person so
你来自一个人的集合，所以
this is a collection of person on the on
这是人的集合
one hand so collection of person to
一方面，这样收集人
collection of list of email here that's
这是电子邮件列表的集合
not probably what I want is that's what
可能不是我想要的是
I want we got a winner but that's not
我希望我们有一个赢家，但这不是
what I want what I really want is a
我想要的是我真正想要的是
collection of person do collection of
收集人做
emails so I want really the collection
电子邮件，所以我真的想要收集
of all the emails one single list how
所有电子邮件中的一个单独列出
would I go about doing that let's draw
我会去做那让我们画画吗
some inspiration from groovy for this
groovy的一些启发
because Java doesn't quite have it
因为Java并没有
so in groovy I'm gonna say list of let's
所以在时髦方面，我要说的是
say one two but I'm gonna say three four
说一二，但我要说三四
and then let's say five and let's go
然后说五个，然后走
ahead and say six seven and let's say
前面说六点七点
eight over here I want to know how many
我想知道八点
elements I have
我有的元素
so I'm gonna say list art size to get
所以我要说列表艺术的大小
the number of elements and it tells me
元素的数量，它告诉我
I've got six elements we know we have
我有六个要素，我们知道我们有
six elements but we actually have eight
六个元素，但实际上我们有八个
elements but we have a list of lists on
元素，但我们有一个列表清单
our hand so the one and two are one
我们的手，所以一和二是一
element 3 4 is 1 5 is the you know
元素3 4是1 5是你知道的
fourth one and five six combine our six
第四和第五六个结合我们的六个
seven combined is one but I really don't
七合一是一个，但我真的不是
want those collection of collection I
想要那些收藏我
want to flat out one single collection
想要整理一个单一的收藏
how do I really get it so if you notice
我怎样才能真正得到它，如果您注意到
over here that's the list of lists I
这是我的清单清单
have on my hand but instead I'm gonna
在我手上，但我要
say let's start flatten and then I'm
说让我们开始展平，然后我
gonna say darts II's and now notice in
要说飞镖II，现在注意
this case when I flatten it out the
这种情况，当我把它弄平
value that I get is eight on my hand
我得到的价值是八
well likewise if I just print out the
同样，如果我只是打印出
flat and the collection it is a flat in
公寓，它是一个公寓的集合
the collection one single collection not
该集合不是一个集合
a collection of collection so flattening
如此扁平化的收藏集
is a function available in a quite a
是一个相当
number of different languages Java quite
Java的不同语言数量
doesn't have it but the good news is
没有它，但好消息是
while Java doesn't have a function to
而Java没有功能
flatten list it does have a way to
展平列表，它确实有办法
flatten streams well almost
几乎将流平整
so what we really want to do is we want
所以我们真正想要做的是
to perform a map operation let's go back
执行地图操作，让我们返回
to the example we saw a minute ago so we
我们在一分钟前看到的例子
want to perform a map operation but
想执行地图操作，但是
while we perform the map operation we
在执行地图操作时，
also want to flatten it technically you
也想从技术上压扁你
could have called it a map flatten but
本可以称它为地图展平，但
that doesn't sound too well so it sounds
听起来不太好，所以听起来
like a tongue twister so they called it
像绕口令，所以他们称之为
flat map so now you know what a flat map
平面图，所以现在您知道什么是平面图
yes
是
use a flat map when you have a
当你有一个平面图
collection of collection in other words
换句话说，集合的集合
when you have one-to-many relationship
有一对多关系时
your candidate most likely is a flat map
您的候选人很可能是平面地图
that's all my mind is wired to think
这就是我所有的想法
about it anytime I have one-to-one
每当我有一对一的时候
transformation I use a map if I want too
转换如果我也想使用地图
many transformation I ask the question
许多转变我问一个问题
maybe it's an application to use a flat
也许这是一个使用平板的应用程序
map in this particular case let's take a
在这种特殊情况下的地图，让我们
look at how we can benefit from flat map
看看我们如何从平面地图中受益
in this particular case in this
在这种情况下
particular example so let's go over here
一个特殊的例子，让我们来看这里
to the code we are dealing with notice
到我们正在处理的代码的通知
we have this collection of collections
我们有这个收藏集
but if you really think about it what is
但是如果你真的考虑一下
this collection yielding this inner loop
这个集合产生这个内部循环
is yielding a collection which is the
正在产生一个集合
triples and we
三倍，我们
put those collections into one flat
将这些收藏放到一个单元中
collection that's what we are trying to
这就是我们想要的收藏
do let's go ahead and run the code real
让我们继续并真正运行代码
quick 3 4 5 8 6 10 we want the same
快速3 4 5 8 6 10我们想要一样
output when we are done but how do we go
完成后输出，但我们如何进行
about doing just that once again let's
再做一次，让我们
highlight all that code let's rewrite
突出显示所有代码，让我们重写
this in functional style so we can say
这是功能性风格，所以我们可以说
return in this case string dot iterate
在这种情况下返回字符串点迭代
and we start with the value 2 why are we
我们从值2开始，为什么
starting with 2 because this loop
从2开始，因为此循环
started with the value of 2 as you can
可以从2开始
see here but notice there was no ending
看到这里，但请注意没有结束
for this particular list in this case it
对于这种情况下的特定列表
came through the break elsewhere that's
经历了其他地方的突破
exactly what we're going to do given
正是我们要做的
element e give me an element E + 1 this
元素e给我元素E +1
is called an infinite stream so infinite
被称为无限流，所以无限
streams have no bounds at all we can
溪流无边无际
keep on going and so as a result we've
继续前进，因此，我们已经
started 2 and then 2 plus 1 is 3 3 plus
开始2然后2加1是3 3加
1 is 4 4 plus 1 is 5 and so on we keep
1是4 4加1是5，依此类推
going
去
of course it's lazy it's not gonna do it
当然，这是懒惰，不是要这么做
until we ask for data so it's on demand
直到我们索要数据，以便按需
so the next thing I'm gonna do with this
所以我接下来要做的是
one is I'm gonna call flatmap on this
一个是我要在这个上叫平面图
one in this case I'm gonna say given a
在这种情况下，我要说的是
value of M I'm going to now say int the
我现在要说的是M的值
stream dart range and I'm gonna start
飞镖射程，我要开始
with the range remember what this went
与范围记住这是怎么回事
from it went from n is 1 but one shy of
从n到1是1，但害羞
M hey that's easy I can start with M one
M嘿，这很容易，我可以从M one开始
and go one shy of M readily so that
随手害羞的M
gives me the for loop for the range of
给我for范围的循环
values but what am I gonna do I'm gonna
价值观，但我该怎么办
say map over here to object and that is
说在这里映射到对象，那就是
because in stream expects to return an
因为插播中期望返回一个
integer but I'm going to return an
整数，但我要返回一个
object in this case and so in this case
在这种情况下是对象
what am I going to map over to this is a
我要映射到的是一个
value of n but I'm gonna return get
n的值，但我要返回得到
triple of the value which is going to be
价值的三倍
whatever the m and n where so M comma n
无论m和n为何M逗号n
that gives us the value from here so
从这里给我们带来价值
this is going to return to us a stream
这将返回给我们
from this particular object we're not
从这个特定的对象，我们不是
done with this of course but the last
当然可以，但是最后
step here is limit and we're going to
这是极限，我们将要
limit this to the number of values we
将其限制为我们的值数
expected and then followed by again our
预期，然后再次是我们的
wonderful collector comes in and we're
优秀的收藏家进来，我们
gonna use the collectors and then
将使用收集器，然后
collectors to
收藏家来
list method in this case so we are going
在这种情况下列出方法，所以我们要
to say here is the to list method to put
要说的是这里的to list方法
this back all into a list eventually so
最终全部归还给清单
where is the in stream coming from let's
串流从哪里来
go ahead and say this in stream is
继续说这是流
coming from the stream so in this case
来自流，所以在这种情况下
that's the code we are ending up with is
那就是我们最终得到的代码是
to simply loop through and print all the
简单地循环并打印所有
values so you can see again the code is
值，以便您可以再次看到代码是
very functional and easy but the trick
非常实用和容易，但是窍门
here was to use a flat map in this case
这里是在这种情况下使用平面地图
knowing that we are dealing with the
知道我们正在处理
one-to-many relationship a flat map will
一对多关系平面图
flatten the list and give us the result
整理列表并给我们结果
eventually and that's exactly what we
最终，这正是我们
did in this particular example so that
在这个特定的例子中做了
uses an idea about how we can do this
关于如何做到这一点的想法
pretty effectively using a flat map I do
我使用平面地图非常有效
have to say that flat map is one of the
不得不说，平面地图是其中之一
charming features in functional
功能上的迷人特征
programming and I kind of keep
编程，我有点
discovering problems where flat map
在平面图上发现问题
becomes useful I traditionally get
传统上变得有用
emails at least once a week from
每周至少发送一次电子邮件
somebody who says how do I solve this
有人说我该怎么解决
problem and my brain is like is this yet
问题，我的大脑就像是这样吗
another flat map question and and
另一个平面图问题和
invariably it turns to be at least one
总是变成至少一个
every week where people are still
每个星期人们仍然在
struggling to really get a grasp of this
努力真正了解这一点
a flat map the last thing I want to show
平面图我想展示的最后一件事
you here is one thing is a very common
你这是一件事是很普遍的
problem but can become really annoying
问题，但会变得很烦人
to solve over time let's actually solve
解决随着时间的推移，让我们实际解决
this by hand and see how painful this
用手看看这有多痛苦
can become so I want I'll take this
可以变成所以我要我接受
problem here and then we will try to
问题在这里，然后我们将尝试
implement it and see how really weird
实施它，看看有多奇怪
our life becomes when we are trying to
当我们试图
do this in functional imperative style
以功能命令式的方式执行此操作
so let's get rid of all of this let's
所以让我们摆脱所有这些
get to the main function real quick and
快速到达主要功能
in the main function what I'm going to
在主要功能中，我要去
do is try to implement the code for this
要做的是尝试为此实现代码
find this come find the sum of square
找到这个来找到平方和
root of K prime numbers starting with n
以n开头的K个质数的根
let's say n is equal to let's throw a
假设n等于让我们抛出一个
number 43 and then let's say in K equals
数字43然后让我们说K等于
to 2 41 let's say some random numbers
到2 41让我们说一些随机数
but how do we implement this code to
但是我们如何实现此代码以
compute the sum of square root of all
计算所有平方根的和
the K numbers well let's give it a try
K数字很好，让我们尝试一下
we can say int index is equal to n into
我们可以说int索引等于n成
count is equal to 0 and then we could
计数等于0，然后我们可以
say double results so double result is
说双重结果，所以双重结果是
equal to 0 when we are done with that we
完成后等于0
want to print the result after all
毕竟想打印结果
but what did we do so far absolutely
但是到目前为止我们到底做了什么
nothing useful we just create a bunch of
没什么用，我们只是创建一堆
these garbage variables that's what we
这些垃圾变量就是我们
did and and then of course what's over
做了，然后当然结束了
next step we're gonna then say while and
下一步，我们要说一会儿，然后
then what do we do after this we say
那我们说完之后我们该怎么办
while count is less than K and your
而计数小于K且您的
brain comes to a screeching halt with
大脑突然停止
the question is it less than or less
问题是小于或小于
than or equal to do you ever ask that
等于或等于你有没有问过
question every single time there's only
每次都只有一个问题
one purpose of code like this to make us
这样的代码的一个目的就是使我们
feel stupid because every time you write
感到愚蠢，因为每次您写
this you heart and say huh and they are
这是你的心，说吧，他们是
trying to find out is it limit or limit
试图找出是极限还是极限
plus one and this is the most vexing
加一，这是最令人烦恼的
thing we've been doing this over and
我们一直在做的事情，
over and every day this is like going to
每一天，这就像
work and feeding us our self in our head
工作，让我们自以为是
right because we can never get this
对，因为我们永远都做不到
straight it's always confusing and we
直总是让人困惑，我们
always kind of write a nun wonder did I
总是写一个修女奇迹我
get it right so it's very vexing as you
弄对了，所以跟你一样很烦
can see then what do I do and then I'm
可以看到然后我该怎么做，然后我就
gonna ask him prime numbers well okay I
要问他素数好吗，我
can write the function for each prime
可以为每个素数编写函数
very easily so public static let's say
很容易，所以说公共静态
boolean in this case is prime implicate
在这种情况下，布尔值是素数
that should be fairly easy to do after
之后应该很容易做到
all so we can simply say return number
这样我们就可以简单地说出退货号码
is greater than 1 and in the stream that
大于1并且在流中
range from o2 to the number and I will
从o2到数字范围，我将
simply say none match and then given a
只需说不匹配，然后给出一个
number I number mod I is equal to zero
数I数mod I等于零
hey that's really as simple as that
嘿，那真的很简单
that's what we did in the beginning
那就是我们一开始所做的
example so we can just bring that in
例子，所以我们可以把它引入
well now that we did that what's the
好了，现在我们做了什么
next step I'm gonna say if the given
下一步，我要说的是
number is a prime so it is index if it's
数字是素数，因此如果是
trying then what am I gonna do result
尝试然后我会做什么结果
this plus equal to math dot square root
此加等于数学点平方根
of the value index and and do the work
的价值指数和做的工作
is this correct no I hear people saying
这是正确的不，我听到有人说
nodding their head saying no it's not
点点头说不，不是
correct what am I missing I have to
纠正我想念的东西
increment the index isn't it now is it
现在增加索引不是吗
correct I see we have to increment the
正确，我看到我们必须增加
count so increment account now is it
算，所以现在是增量帐户
correct it has to be outside isn't it so
纠正它必须在外面不是吗
the count how do you feel about that
伯爵你对此有何看法
where the index count should be here the
索引计数应在此处
count
计数
being commented here but the index
在这里被评论但索引
should be here this is accidental
应该在这里这是偶然的
complexity isn't it that's a lot of work
复杂性不是很多工作
to write this code and of course the
编写这段代码，当然
question is does it work well we can
问题是它是否运作良好，我们可以
only be in good faith to run this and
只本着诚信经营
see what it does it gave us some result
看看它做了什么，给了我们一些结果
but that's a lot of work to write that
但这要写很多工作
simple piece of code shall we try this
简单的一段代码，我们可以尝试一下
again let's go ahead and try this one
再次让我们继续尝试这个
more time well we can leverage our
好一点的时间，我们可以利用我们的
infinite stream here as well so we can
这里也有无限的流，所以我们可以
go back to this code and say doubled
回到这段代码再说一遍
result is equal to stream dart iterate
结果等于流dart迭代
and we are interested from the number n
我们对数字n感兴趣
given a element give me element +1 so we
给定一个元素给我+1个元素
can start iterating from the stream this
可以从流中开始迭代
is called an infinite stream like I
像我一样被称为无限流
mentioned lambdas make it possible to
提到的lambda使得它有可能
create infinite streams this infinite
创建无限流
stream has absolutely no bounds I know
流绝对没有界限，我知道
what you're thinking if it's infinite
你在想什么，如果它是无限的
how long does it go it really goes to
它要走多久
infinity oh my goodness if it's infinity
无限哦，我的天哪，如果无限
where would you store it on the cloud of
您会将其存储在哪里
course but the point really is it is
当然，关键是
absolutely infinite in size isn't it so
绝对无限大小是不是
in this case of course it's gonna yield
在这种情况下当然会屈服
results as and when you request for the
结果以及当您要求
result but then we can go to this and
结果，但是我们可以去做
say dart filter sample is prime and we
说飞镖过滤器样品是主要的，我们
are asking for the prime numbers only
只问素数
but then we can say map well in this
但是我们可以在此说好地图
case we can say map to double and give
情况下我们可以说地图加倍并给
it a value give me the square root of
它给了我一个平方根
the value then we can say dart limit in
该值，那么我们可以说在
this case we'll say okay the question is
这种情况下，我们会说好的，问题是
is it less than K less than or equal to
小于K小于等于
chain it's K time it keep moving you
连锁是K时间让你动起来
don't have to waste your time on such
不必浪费时间在这样的
trivial things and then you perform the
琐碎的事情，然后您执行
sum operation on it now look at the code
现在对它求和运算看一下代码
below compared to the code in the top
与顶部的代码相比
the code in the top is filled with
顶部的代码充满
accidental complexity the code in the
意外的复杂性
bottom removes all those accidental
底部清除所有意外
complexity very nicely as we can see we
如我们所见，复杂性非常好
don't have to put in so much effort at
不必在
all so all we are doing here is we are
所以我们在这里所做的就是
iterating through all the values
遍历所有值
starting from n lazily of course we get
从n懒惰开始，我们当然得到
all the prime numbers from n we could
来自n的所有素数
the square root of all the prime numbers
所有素数的平方根
from N and then finally of course what
从N开始，然后当然是什么
we are doing here is the extracting only
我们在这里所做的只是提取
kVAL use out of it well every single one
kVAL每次都用完
of these highlighted code are lazy
这些突出显示的代码是懒惰的
operations they don't do eagerly
他们不急着进行的操作
including limit it doesn't do things
包括限制，它不会做任何事情
eagerly at all and then there's some
急切地然后有一些
being the terminal operation is the one
作为终端操作是
that triggers the execution in the case
在这种情况下触发执行
of streams it's always the tail that
的流总是尾巴
wags the dog until you have the terminal
摇狗直到有终端
method the engine of streams would not
方法流引擎不会
start kicking in so that waits until
开始踢，直到等到
that point to start really ticking so in
那一点开始真正地滴答作响
this case of course the beauty of this
这种情况当然是这个美丽
approach is look at the code in the top
方法是看顶部的代码
this is what I call as accidental
这就是我所说的偶然
complexity I have a little challenge for
复杂性我有一点挑战
you put this code in front of somebody
你把这段代码放在别人面前
and ask them to read it and sit in front
并请他们阅读并坐在前面
of them and watch their eyeball their
他们，看着他们的眼球
eyeball does this and then it does this
眼球这样做，然后这样做
and then it is shaking here that's
然后它在这里发抖
called the point of confusion you're
叫做混乱点
still trying to figure out what this
仍在试图找出这是什么
code is doing right and if a business
代码做对了，如果一项业务
analyst comes to you and says hey I see
分析师来找你，说，嘿，我明白了
you're looking at our code what is this
您正在查看我们的代码，这是什么
girl doing and your response normally is
女孩在干，你的反应通常是
that's what I'm trying to figure out you
那就是我要弄清楚你的
shut up and that's how we feel about it
闭嘴，这就是我们的感受
very frustrated but you can have a
很沮丧，但是你可以
healthy conversation with them
与他们进行健康对话
yeah dude let's talk about it given all
是的，花花公子让我们谈论一下
the values from n I'm getting all the
我得到的所有n的值
prime numbers from n I'm getting the
我得到的素数
square of the values but only K of them
值的平方，但只有K
and totaling them up is that what you
总结起来就是你
really wanted and it becomes really easy
真的想要，这变得非常容易
to execute the code as well so it
同时执行代码
becomes very convenient to discus about
讨论起来变得非常方便
the code and interact with it as well so
代码并与之交互
to summarize what we talked about here
总结我们在这里谈论的内容
we went from a very cryptic code in this
我们从一个非常神秘的代码中
example to something very concise but we
例子很简洁，但我们
are really able to use infinite streams
真的能够使用无限流
and lazy evaluation if you ask me what
和懒惰的评价，如果你问我什么
is the big deal about functional style
函数式风格有多重要
of programming and and I've been trying
编程，我一直在尝试
to struggle and learn about functional
努力学习功能
programming for a lot of time and and me
编程很多时间，而我
include that a lot of speakers would
包括很多演讲者会
tell you oh my gosh if you're doing
告诉你，哦，天哪，如果你在做
functional programming you should honor
您应该尊重的函数式编程
immutability you should really not you
不变性你真的不应该
know you should use higher-order
知道你应该使用高阶
functions you should really focus on
您应该真正关注的功能
writing code like this but I think those
编写这样的代码，但我认为那些
are your important stuff but that's not
是你重要的东西，但这不是
the real main real benefit or the
真正的主要实际利益或
excitement when functional programming
函数编程时的兴奋
to me the real excitement is all that in
对我来说，真正的兴奋是
functional purity and the programming
功能纯度和编程
with immutability all that where it is
永恒不变
leading us as to this one exciting real
带领我们来到这一激动人心的现实
feature which is laziness because if you
懒惰的特征，因为如果你
are lazy both in life and in programming
在生活和编程上都懒惰
the best people ever most efficient
最有效率的最好的人
people ever are the lazy ones so you
人们曾经是懒惰的人，所以你
just say hey I'm gonna postpone
只是说嘿，我要推迟
execution until I can no longer postpone
执行，直到我不再推迟
it and by waiting until that point you
然后等到那一点
can be really efficient and that's what
可以真正有效，那就是
this code is showing us how lazy
这段代码向我们展示了多么懒
evaluation can open up doors for not
评估可以为不敞开大门
only runtime efficiency but it can also
只有运行时效率高，但它也可以
open the door for things like infinite
打开无限之门
streams which give us a programming tool
流为我们提供了编程工具
that we very rarely exploit when we
当我们
write code in Java but this opens up
用Java编写代码，但这打开了
doors for some really nice way of
门的一些非常好的方式
implementing things along the way
一路实现
so essentially where this leads us to is
所以从本质上讲，这导致我们
we are able to express code in Java this
我们可以用Java表达代码
is kind of like you know coming back to
有点像你知道回到
Java and and being excited all about it
Java并为此感到兴奋
one more time and this is one of the
再过一次，这是其中之一
things honestly that excites me you know
老实说让我兴奋的事情
of all these decades later every single
在所有这些几十年后的每一个人
morning I get up to write code and to me
早上我起来写代码给我
coding is not a profession coding is an
编码不是专业编码是一种
addiction and to me the reason coding is
成瘾，对我来说，编码的原因是
exciting is being a programmer is like
令人兴奋的是，成为一名程序员就像
being a kid in a candy store every
每次在糖果店当小孩
single day and that's what really
一天，那才是真正的
excites me is to be able to write this
让我兴奋的是能够写这个
kind of code and to be able to express
类型的代码并能够表达
them in ways that we just haven't had a
他们以我们没有过的方式
chance to express in language like Java
有机会用Java之类的语言表达
before but we are able to do this which
以前，但我们能够做到这一点
is very very powerful so as you as you
非常强大，就像你一样
continue your journey on going from
继续您的旅程
imperative functional style of
命令式函数式风格
programming to summarize things that can
编程以总结可以
help you are you know think about
帮助您，您知道思考
formulating the words in English ask the
用英语写单词问
question what am i doing and that's a
问我在做什么，那是一个
struggle we have to try a little bit
挣扎，我们必须尝试一点
harder and when you formulate the
更难，当你制定
problem in English and say this is what
英语的问题，说这是什么
I'm doing then you start looking for
我在做然后你开始寻找
methods that might closely match with
可能与之紧密匹配的方法
your English description and maybe take
您的英文描述，可能需要
on those functions and and use it the
在这些功能上，并使用它
second a part of that journey is as you
第二部分是你的旅程
walk through the JDK libraries and
遍历JDK库和
functions make note of functions you may
功能记下您可能会使用的功能
not have seen before and and take a look
以前没看过，看看
at hey this is interesting I haven't
嘿，这很有趣，我没有
seen this what problem this probably is
看到这可能是什么问题
solving that could be a really nice way
解决那可能是一个非常好的方法
to learn that as well and a third thing
也要学习到第三点
I would
我会
strongly encouraged as I learn a lot by
我从中学到了很多东西，因此受到极大的鼓励
being critiqued going and sitting next
被批评要坐下
to somebody and saying hey I'm writing
对某人说嘿我在写
this in functional style why don't you
在函数式风格上，为什么不
take a look at what I'm doing maybe have
看一下我在做什么
an idea and even if they may not have an
一个想法，即使他们可能没有
answer just talking to somebody really
真的只是和某人说话
helps us do you aren't angled some of
可以帮助我们您对某些事情不感兴趣
our you know a brain which is stuck in a
我们知道一个卡在
particular comfort zone and might open
特殊的舒适区，可能会打开
up ways to really think about solutions
真正思考解决方案的方法
the way you may not have had a chance to
您可能没有机会的方式
think about and that can be a really
考虑一下，这可能是一个真正的
good learning experience of shared
共享的良好学习经验
learning experience as well so that's
学习经验也是如此
basically what I have hope that was
基本上我希望那是
useful thank you
有用的谢谢
[Applause]
[掌声]